straight to the point today I'll be
showing you everything you need to know
to become profitable by trading support
and resistance supply and demand or
order blocks I will be walking you
through exactly how I spot the most
accurate levels to trade around and I'll
be walking you through the strategies
that have help me accumulate an 87%
return in Forex this year while only
trading about twice a week a 42% return
in stocks and a 120% return in crypto in
2023 the strategies and techniques I'll
be showing you today work on any time
frame and in any market so if that
sounds like something you want to learn
go ahead and click that like button for
me go ahead subscribe if you are new and
I'll see you right after the intro and
[Music]
disclaimer so this is the part of the
video where I would normally Define what
support and resistance are but there
seems to be a lot of confusion around
this so I want to clear this up right
now on the screen you can see three
definitions the definitions of these are
the definition of support and resistance
the definition of supply and demand and
the definition of order blocks read
through them pause the video if you have
to what you'll notice is that these
three things are wildly similar so in
this video what I want you to understand
is we're just looking for major levels
of structure that are likely to push the
market around it does not matter what we
call them it doesn't matter if you want
to call them support and resistance
supply and demand or order blocks they
are all essentially looking for the same
exact thing so in this video I'm going
to be teaching you my rules for finding
major levels of structure the market is
likely to react from and that we're
likely to find profitable trading
opportunities in but the rules I'm going
to share with you aren't the exact rules
for support and resistance or the exact
rules for supply and demand or the exact
rules for order blocks it's more of a
combination of all of these things and
the main reason I wanted to share this
with you is because I don't want you to
get caught up on what it's called more
so I want you to learn the concept of
finding these areas in the market and
getting profitable trading opportunities
inside of these zones in a nutshell
there are two different major levels of
structure that we're going to be paying
attention to for Possible Trading
opportunities those two different levels
are Trend continuation and counter Trend
levels of major structure Trend
continuation levels are known as roll
reversal levels and on the screen you
can see an article from Fidelity feel
free to pause the video and check that
article out but essentially what it says
is all often times if a market is
trending higher the previous resistance
level will become support and often
times when the market is trending lower
the previous support level will become
resistance now I know this is very basic
but again we're starting with the basics
just for those of you who are brand new
then we'll move on some more advanced
material let's go ahead and point out
these roll reversal levels and I'm going
to talk you through the psychology
behind them and why they actually work
to create an area where we can find
accurate trading opportunities if you
look on the chart here you can see that
price was pushing up from here we get to
this high and then demand begins to
decrease for this asset which causes it
to pull back at some point during this
pullback the price gets so low that
people see this as a deal this is kind
of like a major sale going on on a
product and if it gets to a certain
price let's say a TV is 50% off you're
much more likely to buy that TV when
it's 50% off that's what happens after
pullbacks so often times we'll see the
increase of an asset followed by the
decrease in demand which causes a
decrease in price followed by that asset
being considered on sell by majority of
the market which then causes prices to
push into Trend continuation making new
higher highs now what has happened in
this situation as well is that right
here at this first High there have been
a lot of sellers try to take control and
not only try to take control but just
sell the market in general expecting
this to be a complete reversal and
trying to capture a lot of profit by
selling the market and by the way for
you beginners selling the market means
you make money as the price of an asset
goes down and obviously buying is the
opposite where you make profit as the
price goes up but this is what they were
expecting they sold right here expecting
price to continue lower so what do you
think happens to them if they sell right
here and then they see price drop a bit
they get excited but then they see price
push much higher well in this case they
are losing money when you lose money you
get scared when you get scared you want
to get away from that fear so the way
that they get away from the fear is that
when price pushes back down and gets to
the level where they are Break Even they
buy the market and what I mean by they
buy the market if you're a seller here
in order to get out of your position you
have to buy back into the market so the
initial pushup from a previous level of
resistance that has now become support
is because of this it is because of
sellers that have been through Pain by
Price pushing higher deciding to get out
of a trade to get rid of that pain
around break even so that's what the
initial buying pressure is and then if
you combine that with the price of this
asset being on sale because that's
essentially what a pullback is that's
the price of an asset being on sale if
we get this pullback this asset now on
sale and if a majority of Market
participants agree that this asset is on
sale this is how you actually spill it
excuse me then what will happen is we
will see Trend continuation and this
continues as price continues up until we
get some type of reversal so if you'll
look back here's what I want you to
notice if we look here where did price
after pulling back breaking Above This
resistance level find support right at
that pre previous resistance level right
and if we look back again it happens
again we have price pushing higher we
have a pullback that pullback comes into
this previous level of resistance then
we see price pushing higher so again
what's Happening Here is we're getting
sellers that were scared because price
went above their initial entry they're
losing money here they want to get rid
of that fear they want to get rid of the
position they were not correct they were
expecting price to keep going lower so
what they're going to do is a lot of
them are going to decide to exit their
sell position at this previous level
where they went short trying to sell the
market and that's going to cause buying
pressure because when they exit their
position they have to exit it with a Buy
trade now let's take a look at a bearish
version of this it's a very simple
concept it should be pretty easy to
understand at this point we have prices
pushing lower we have buyers trying to
step in and take control remember these
buyers are expecting this to be a price
reversal well when that doesn't happen
price continues lower those buyers are
losing money and since they're losing
money they're in fear they do not want
to lose money so the way they avoid
losing money is they get out somewhere
around Break Even which was the previous
level of supports when they see this
pullback push up this is a great level
for them to say hey I realize now that I
was wrong about this B trade because
prices have now closed below this
previous swing low since I'm wrong I
want to get out of my position right
where I bought in right at break even
and that initially causes sell orders
and if those sell orders continue that's
what causes the continuation in Trend so
for a quick recap when we're looking for
bullish Trend continuation we're going
to be looking at the previous level of
resistance we're going to wait for price
to come back to that level and that
level can become support obviously
there's a lot more that goes into it
than this and we're going to discuss
some details and a lot more rules we
have for this a little later in the
video video but I want everyone to
understand this part of it before we
move forward cuz otherwise you're going
to be really confused when we talk about
more advanced concepts for a bearish
example of this we're going to be
looking at previous support becoming
resistance you guessed it so that's what
we're looking at in terms of the rooll
reversal and the trend continuation side
of spotting major levels of structure
along with the other rules we're going
to talk about in just a second but for
now let's dive into the counter Trend
major structure levels that we're going
to be looking for for counter Trend
levels let's say that we have a market
that's done something like this then we
start trending down and then we start
trending back up at the point that we
start trending back up wherever price is
the highest swing high price is made by
the way this is for a resistance level
counter Trend trade at that resistance
level I'm going to look up and to the
left and find the very next resistance
level that price will inevitably hit if
it continues higher so if price
continues higher it will absolutely hit
this level this is going to be the the
only level I Mark out for counter Trend
at that point in price so let me go over
that one more time really quickly we
have a market pushing higher pushing
higher pushing higher then it starts to
reverse right during this downtrend at
this point right here where would I be
looking for possible counter Trend
trades we've started a new downtrend
with this one two three move so at this
point where am I looking for counter
Trend buy trades at this point I would
be looking for buy
trades right there right at this next
support level that price will hit if it
continues now notice for counter Trend
trades I did not pick the previous
resistance level here and there's a
really good reason for that I've noticed
that these levels are not quite as
accurate as looking for just support
levels when you're looking for buy
trades and just resistance levels when
you're looking for sell trades we're
going to take a look at a lot of
examples of these when we go through the
advanced rules but essentially if price
is right here I'm just looking for the
next level where price has been
supported in the past I'm not looking at
the previous resistance level for
counter Trend trades I'm only looking
for that next level where price has been
supported in the past and that will be
the level that I look for Possible
Trading opportunities to the buy side
from so for an example on real charts
what trend are we in right now here on
the pound New Zealand well we've had a
one two three move and we've since even
created another lower low this should be
a low high if we're going to continue in
Trend pushing lower so at this point
here's how I would actually do this in
real time this is real time on the pound
New Zealand what I'm going to be doing
is placing a horizontal line at that
previous low I'm then going to scrunch
up my charts until I see the next level
of support price is going to hit if this
downtrend continues that is very easy to
spot in this case we look below the
lowest swing low that's been made and we
look to our left and we can see this is
the next level of support
that price is going to hit if in fact we
do continue in this downtrend and break
into new lower lows so with that being
the case all I have to do is pull this
down to that level and I can create my
area of counter Trend support that I'll
be looking in for possible buy trades
here on the pound New Zealand again if
we do in fact continue in this downtrend
this is where I look for that pop before
the continuation or even a full reversal
if we get lucky enough for an example on
Resistance here we have the Alie New
Zealand which is currently in this
uptrend right as we've been in this
uptrend price is obviously right here at
the moment and what will I do in order
to spot a counter Trend level that I can
make possible trades in I'm going to put
a horizontal line at the very top of the
Swing high of this uptrend I'm going to
look up and to the left and find the
latest level of resistance looking left
and I'm going to use that area as my
counter Trend resistance area if we
scroll the chart back it's really easy
to see that this is that zone so here on
this chart that's where I'll be looking
for possible counter Trend trades is in
this area of the next resistance level
price will hit if it continues up in
this uptrend and breaks Above This level
so that was the most basic version of
finding Trend continuation and counter
Trend major levels of structure to trade
around but obviously that's not all we
need what I mean by that is if you use
the information that you've learned so
far that's not going to make you
profitable we have to add other
conditions to these levels in order to
make them profitable areas to trade
using it by itself doesn't mean anything
and after adding those other conditions
to make them profitable levels and major
levels of structure we can trade around
after doing that we also have to add in
entries stops and targets to create a
full strategy and turn this into a
money-making opportunity so that's what
we're going to dive into right now with
the other conditions we need to see
we're going to start off with Trend
continuation and we're looking at a
bearish example here on the pound dollar
we're going to add two things to our
Trend continuation version of spotting
these major levels of structure number
one is the 50 EMA that is the Blue Line
you see on the screen and what this is
going to do is make it super easy to
spot the trend of the market for our
bearish train continuation trades what
we're looking for in terms of our major
level of structure is the previous level
of support to become resistance right
well with this added condition what
we're saying is that both of these must
occur below the 50 EMA so we need not
only our support level to happen that
breaks below right that price breaks we
need that to happen below the 50 EMA we
also need the pullback to stay below the
50 EMA that gets to that level and if
that is the case then we still have a
valid level so the first thing we're
going to add as a condition is that all
of this must occur below the 50 EMA and
obviously this is just for the trend
continu ation version of this not for
the counter Trend so for Trend
continuation that's one of the
conditions we are adding another
condition we're adding is that this
level must have been tested multiple
times so here's what that looks like
whenever we're looking back at a level
we have our downtrend one two three move
we have our previous level of support
and we want to make sure that this level
hasn't just been tested one time in
through year but also has been tested in
the past this would be a perfect example
of this as this level has been tested
four times
as support which means it now has a
really high likelihood of becoming
resistance for this market so adding
those two conditions to your Trend
continuation trades will make them
wildly more profitable and I often get
the question how far back should I look
when I'm looking for multiple tests of a
level I don't have a rule for that but
if you need a rule I would say between
200 and 300 candles and yes what I mean
by that is you have to go count every
one of these candles and see if there's
300 on the screen totally joking you can
use the ruler tool which is right here
and all you have to do is pull it
sideways and you'll see a little number
that says 316 bars that means we're
looking at 316 bars for as far sideways
as we're going with this specific ruler
tool that's the easiest way to look at
it and the reason I do that instead of
saying look back a month or look back
two months is because it depends on the
time frame you're on the things I'm
talking about in this video work for any
time frame so if you're on the one
minute chart you obviously don't want to
be looking back a month that's way too
much data if you're on the daily chart
you're probably going to have to look
back further than a month so stick to
around 200 to 300 candles 200 300 Bars
is what we want to look at when we're
looking for that second test of a level
in this case what do we have our
downtrend we have multiple tests right
and we have this occurring below the 50
EMA so this would be a perfect example
of a trend continuation level that I
would actually look for trades in based
on all the conditions for an accurate
level of structure with this being the
case let's go ahead and push price
forward and see what happens price
eventually gets in this level this is
when I would actually start looking for
a trade and as you can see after coming
into this level prices did fall pretty
dramatically and I know right now you're
probably thinking so how would you enter
the trade once prices got into this area
and that's something we're going to
discuss in just a second first though I
want to give you all the conditions for
a counter Trend level of structure that
way we have the levels of structure
completely out of the way before we talk
about entry stops and targets and the
full trading strategy for our counter
Trend example we're looking at the
dollar Yen what trend are we in right
now what has the dollar Yen done most
recently well most recently we've had
this one two three move putting us into
a downtrend again one two being the
pullback three being an impulsive move
that breaks below the pullback since
we're in a downtrend that means I'm
going to be looking for Trend
continuation and also I'm going to be
looking for counter Trend trades the way
I'm going to be looking for counter
Trend trades is how what am I going to
be looking for well the first step is to
put a horizontal line where price
currently is at this point I know I'm
looking down and to the left for what
for the last level that price was
supported by and I know that level is
going to be where I'm going to be
looking for possible counter Trend
bounces out of now the condition we're
adding to the counter Trend way of
trading is the same as the one we added
to the trend continuation version we're
just adding the fact that it has to be
tested multiple times obviously the
moving average is a relevant during a
counter Trend opportunity but we are
adding the rule that we need to see that
level tested multiple times but our
first step let's look down and to the
left and see the next level of support
price will inevitably hit if it
continues lower if we're scrolling left
now we see that that level is right here
now by the way I do not pay attention to
these long wigs at all when pointing out
structure levels so just kind of
discount this Wick if you can so right
here again the level that we're looking
at is is right here it's this level of
support this is the level of support
Price is Right Here remember this is the
level of support price will hit if it
continues lower in the downtrend now the
second question I have to ask myself is
is this level a level that was tested
multiple times the answer to that is
obviously yes we have one two three
tests with this little resistance area
we have another test here we have a
little support a little support and our
final support before price went higher
so this matches the criteria for
everything I need to see all in all
conditions included for a counter Trend
trading opportunity for me to start
looking for possible entries in this
specific Zone let's click play and see
what happens at this point I would be
looking for entries in this area and
again we'll talk about entries in just a
second but as you can see it did in fact
cause this big bounce out of price so
those are the conditions that I use in
order to spot really accurate areas to
place trades from but those are just
conditions and conditions do not mean
you're going to be a profitable Trader
you could know so many conditions it's
not even funny but the point of
conditions conditions like support and
resistance supply and demand order
blocks I don't care if you're learning
about indicators moving averages the
whole reason you are learning about all
of those things it's with the main goal
of creating a profitable trading
strategy with them there is no magic
bullet there is nothing that's going to
be just that one thing will make you
money as a Trader what you're going to
have to do is combine these conditions
with specific entry reasons and a
specific way of taking a stop loss
managing your risk and a specific way of
taking your targets and accepting your
gains all of that combines to create a
profitable trading strategy which will
make you money in the long run as a
Trader but just having conditions is
irrelevant if you don't add those things
to it so although I just shared with you
the conditions I use to find the most
accurate areas in the market for my own
personal Trading it's not enough we now
need to talk about a full strategy and
get into entries stops and targets so I
actually have a number of different
entries that I utilize inside of these
major levels of structure but if I tried
to teach all of them this video would be
about 6 hours long so instead of doing
that what I'm going to do is share with
you my favorite way to enter Trend
continuation trades when utilizing major
structure levels and my favorite way to
enter into counter Trend trades when
utilizing these major structure levels
now the way I enter into two Trend
continuation trades is a lot more
aggressive and the reason for that is
that those trades tend to have a bit
more accuracy I'm going with the trend
in those trades while on the other side
of that coin I tend to use a more
conservative entry most of the time when
I'm looking at counter Trend trading
opportunities but right now let's focus
on our Trend continuation entry stops
and targets so here we have the dollar
Canada we're currently on the 4-Hour
chart as you can see we are currently in
an uptrend so what has just happened
here on this pair is we pushed up
creating R1 R2 as our pullback and we
broke Above This resistance level with
our number three move which is the
impulsive move that broke above the
previous swing high in this case what am
I going to be doing for a trend
continuation level well I'm going to be
marking off this previous level of
resistance what are our other rules that
we must use in order to make this a
level we can actually trade from well my
other rule is that this level must have
happened above the 50 EMA is that the
case yes it is and the other rule I have
is that it must be a level tested
multiple times looking left we can see
that this was used as a major level of
resistance here as well making this one
two times that it's been tested that's
all I need now I know I'm inside of a
zone that I can look for potential
trading opportunities out of so if we
push price forward here we can see we're
already inside of this Zone and what I'm
going to be doing as long as we stay
above the 50 EMA remember even this it
can be touching the 50 EMA but I want
the close of my entry to be above the 50
EMA and for entries on this trend
continuation trade one of my favorites
to use is an engulfing candle a
Candlestick pattern that closes above
the high of the previous candle if I
zoom in here you can see that that
happens right here so here we have an
engulfing candle which means a candle
with the body larger than the previous
body of the previous candle now this
must be a color change as well meaning
we must go from red to Green on that
Candlestick and my other added rule that
I use for these trades and these trading
opportunities is we must have the
engulfing candle closing above the high
of the previous candle since all of that
is true in this case what I'm going to
be doing is placing an entry at the
close of that candle so this would be my
actual reason for entry for stops and
targets I normally actually manage these
positions if they're TR continuation but
that's a bit complicated to go into here
on YouTube and here for this video I'm
trying to keep this video a little
shorter today so for stops I'm going to
be going below that previous swing low
after our engulfing candle or the swing
low that happened during this pullback
whichever one that is I'm going below
the swing low of the pullback with my
stop loss and then for a Target
something I use often whenever I'm
taking fixed targets and I'm not
managing the position I utilize a 1.4
to1 reward risk ratio quite often so
that's what we're going to do for these
examples today and as you can see this
is the way that trade setup would look
if we click play you'll see that this
trade played out and the reason it did
is because I like showing winning
examples but understand that this
strategy also has losses we'll talk a
little more about that in a second but
here you can see a trade that worked out
well because we waited for price to get
to an area of structure that was very
likely to become support we then had a
rules-based way that we entered the
market with that Eng engulfing candle
that closed above the previous candle
and because we followed the plan and the
market reacted well to our analysis we
came out as profitable and made money on
the specific trade now let's talk about
the counter Trend entry that I use most
often and the one that I find to be the
most profitable and first let's take a
look at the chart now we're on the pound
dollar here on the pound dollar how are
we going to find this level of structure
that we could trade from this major
level we're going to put a horizontal
line where price is now cuz we're in
what type of trend this Market has
pushed up to a high higher low higher
high higher low and created a new higher
high we're currently in an uptrend with
that being the case and we're going to
be trading counter Trend in this example
we're going to put a horizontal line at
the highest point price has gotten to
then go up into the left to find our
major level let's scroll back the chart
here is the next level of resistance
price is going to hit so with that being
the case we're going to make this our
resistance level and this is going to be
the area we look at for possible trades
now what's the next question we have to
ask ourselves has this level been tested
multiple times here we have one two
three tests of resistance along with
another Little Resistance here that
counts for me so that's going to be a
yes so this is in fact a Zone where I'll
be looking for Possible Trading
opportunities now for counter Trend
trades I do something a little different
wherever I find my zone I drop down one
time frame to find my entry so right now
we're looking at the Zone on the daily
chart I'm GNA be dropping down to the 4
Hour chart to look for the entry if my
zone was on the 4 Hour chart I'd go down
to the 1 hour if my zone was on the 1
hour I would go to 30 minutes so on and
so forth you can see my time frames up
here that's the ones I dropped down to
so we're on the daily I'm going to drop
down to the 4our for us to find our
entry now we are here on the 4our chart
this is the area we pointed out back on
the daily and for the entry on a 4our
chart I use something very simple it is
just chart patterns more specifically
and the ones that I use most often are
double tops in levels of resistance and
double Bottoms in levels of support but
I have to utilize a specific entry on
these double tops I'll show that to you
now here we push up and we end up
getting this nice double top we have one
top here the neckline of our double top
the second top the entry reason I need a
specific reason that I'm going to click
the sell button on a double top and that
entry reason is going to be a red candle
so after my double top I want to see a
red candle and as soon as I see that red
candle after my double top that is when
I'm going to utilize actually placing
the trade this would be when I would
place the trade coming off that double
top I would have a stop loss above the
highest point of that double top and
again we're going to utilize the same
targets but as I said earlier I do
manage these positions quite often but
here for these examples we're going to
use a 1.4 to one reward to risk ratio
let's see how that plays out as you can
see price pushed down and did in fact
hit our targets and and this is actually
a trade that I had recently earlier last
week so now you have a full way of
trading around support and resistance
supply and demand order blocks whatever
you want to call it levels of structure
that are likely to push the market
around you have your entry stop and
Target you also have how you're going to
identify these zones in a very
rules-based way and that's going to help
you stay consistent and utilizing this
is something that's helped me become and
continue to be a profitable Trader now
this is not all you need to know and
obviously every strategy comes with
losses so it's going to lose at times
you're going to have losing streaks and
draw Downs no matter what strategy you
use and that's why it's so important for
you to learn and understand the other
parts of trading like Risk Management
and trading psychology now those things
aren't something I have time to get into
today in this video but if you want to
learn some other strategies that I use
in my own personal trading along with
get a full organized University style
course that will teach you every aspect
of trading you need to stay consistently
profitable then we do have some space
available right now now in the TTC forx
University in the University you'll get
a full course teaching you everything
you need to know to become a profitable
Trader and along with that you'll be
getting two to five emails a week that
are trades I'm actually placing based on
the strategies you're learning the prot
trader report every Monday which is me
showing you the levels of structure I'm
paying attention to for the week ahead
and on top of that you'll also get
priority coaching support which means
any questions you have you can email and
it will be me personally answering those
questions to give this more of a mentor
worship style and so that I can help
guide you on your path to becoming a
profitable Trader if you're interested
in that to find out all the details all
you got to do is click the top Link in
the description or go to
www.tcf university.com if not then I
still hope you enjoyed this video hope
it taught you something if it did click
that like button for me go ahead and
subscribe if you're new and I'll catch
you in the next video see you soon